inummommuimmiCONTENTS imima•immilmima




ANALYSIS OF AKTU PAPERS (2013-14 TO 2017-18) (A-1 A to A-8 A)
UNIT-1 BASIC COMPONENTS OF A CONTROL SYSTEM
                                  (1-1 A to 1-38 A)
    Basic Components of a control system, Feedback and its effect, 
    types of feedback control systems. Block diagrams Reduction and 
    signal flow graphs, Modeling of Physical systems: electrical 
    networks, mechanical systems elements, equations of mechanical 
    systems, sensors and encoders in control systems, DC motors in 
    control systems, Analogous Systems.

UNIT-2 : STATE-VARIABLE ANALYSIS   (2-1 A to 2-31 A)
    Vector matrix representation of state equation, state transition matrix, state- 
    transition equation, relationship between state equations& high-order differential 
    equations, relationship between state equations & transfer functions. Similarity 
    Transformation, Decomposition of transfer functions, Controllability & 
    observability, Eigen Value and Eigen Vector, Diagonalization.

UNIT-3 : TIME DOMAIN ANALYSIS OF CONTROL SYSTEMS
                                  (3-1 A to 3-27 A)
    Time response of continuous data systems, typical test signals for 
    the time response of control systems, unit step response & time- 
    domain specifications, Steady-State error, time response of a first 
    order system, transient response of a prototype second order system.

UNIT-4 : STABILITY OF LINEAR CONTROL SYSTEM (4-1 A to 4-29 A) 
    Bounded-input bounded-output stability continuous data systems, 
    zero-input & asymptotic stability of continuous data systems, Routh 
    Hurwitz criterion. Root-Locus Technique: Introduction, Properties
    of the Root Loci, Design aspects of the Root Loci.

UNIT-5 : FREQUENCY DOMAIN ANALYSIS (5-1 A to 5-38 A)
    M, (resonant peak) and wr (resonant frequency) and bandwidth of 
    the prototype Second order system, effects of adding a zero to the 
    forward path, effects of adding a pole 1-0 the forward path, Polar 
    Plot, Nyquist stability criterion, relative stability: gain margin and 
    phase margin, stability analysis with the Bode plot.

SHORT QUESTIONS                   (SQ-1A to SQ-16A)

SOLVED PAPERS (2013-14 TO 2017-18)(SP-1A to SP-18A)

