REC602                              DIGITAL COMMUNICATION


  Unit                                          Topic                                          Lectures

          Principles of digital data transmission: Digital Data transmission, Line coding review, Pulse 
          shaping, Scrambling, Digital receivers, Eye diagram, Digital carrier system. Method of 
    I     generation and detection of coherent & non-coherent binary ASK, FSK & PSK, Differential 
          phase shift keying, Quadrature modulation techniques. (QPSK and MSK), M-ary Digital     08
          carrier Modulation.

          Fundamentals of probability theory & random process : Concept of Probability, Random 
          variable, Statistical averages, Correlation, Sum of Random Variables, Central Limit 
  11      Theorem, Random Process, Classification of Random Processes Power spectral density,     08
          Multiple random Processes.

          Performance Analysis of Digital communication system: Optimum linear Detector for 
          Binary polar signaling, General Binary Signaling, Coherent Receivers for Digital Carrier 
  HI      Modulations, Signal Space Analysis of Optimum Detection, Vector Decomposition of 
          White Noise Random processes, General Expression for Error Probability of optimum       08
          receivers

          Spread spectrum Communications: Frequency Hopping Spread Spectrum(FHSS) systems, 
          Direct Sequence Spread Spectrum, Code Division Multiple Access of DSSS, Multiuser 
          Detection, OFDM Communications

  IV      Introduction to information theory: Measure of Information, Source Encoding, Error Free 08
          Communication over a Noisy Channel. Capacity of a discrete and Continuous Memory less 
          channel.

          Error Correcting codes: Hamming sphere, hamming distance and Hamming bound, relation 
          between minimum distance and error detecting and correcting capability
  V
          Linear block codes: encoding and syndrome decoding. Cyclic codes: encoder and decoder   08

          for systematic cyclic codes. Convolution codes, code tree and Trellis diagram, Viterbi and 
          sequential decoding, Burst error correction, Turbo codes.




  Text Book:

      1. B.P. Lathi, "Modern Digital and Analog communication Systems", 4th Edition, Oxford University Press, 
          2010.
      2. RishabhAnand, Communication Systems, Khanna Publishing House, Delhi.

  Reference Books:

      1. H. Taub, D L Schilling, Gaut2mSaha, "Principles of Communication", 3rd Edition, Tata McGraw-Hill 
          Publishing Company Ltd.
      2. John G. Proakis, 'Digital Communications", 4th Edition, McGraw-Hill International.
      3. Simon Haykin, "Communication Systems", 4th Edition, Wiley India.
      4. H P HSU & D Mitra, "Analog and Digital Communications", 2nd Edition, Tata McGraw-Hill Publishing 
          Company Ltd.

