                 CONTENTS


        PAS-502/ RAS-602 : SOCIOLOGY


UNIT-I : INTRODUCTION TO INDUSTRIAL SOCIOLOGY
                                    (1-1 U to 1-20 U)
    Nature, Scope and Importance of Industrial Sociology. Social 
    Relations in Industry, Social Organisation in Industry - 
    Bureaucracy, Scientific Management and Human Relations.


UNIT-2 : RISE AND DEVELOPMENT OF INDUSTRY (2-1 U to 2-19 U) 
    Early Industrialism — Types of Productive Systems — The Manorial
    or Feudal system. The Guild system, The domestic or putting-out 
    system, and the Factory system. Characteristics of the factory 
    system. Causes and Consequences of industrialization. Obstacles 
    to and Limitations of Industrialization.


UNIT-3 : INDUSTRIALIZATION IN INDIA (3-1 U to 3-22 U)
    Industrialization in India. Industrial Policy Resolutions — 1956. 
    Science, Technology and Innovation Policy of India 2013.


UNIT-4 : CONTEMPORARY ISSUES        (4-1 U to 4-34 U)
    Grievances and Grievance handling Procedure. Industrial Disputes: 
   causes, Strikes and Lockouts. Preventive Machinery of Industrial 
   Disputes: Schemes of Workers Participation in Management- Works 
   Committee, Collective Bargaining, Bi-partite & Tri-partite 
   Agreement, Code of Discipline, Standing Orders. Labour courts & 
   Industrial Tribunals.


UNIT-5 : VISUALIZING THE FUTURE     (5-1 U to 5-11 U)
   Models of industrialization - Collectivist, anarchist, free market, 
   environmentalist, etc. Cultural issues, consumer society and 
   sociological concerns.

SHORT QUESTIONS                    (SQ-lU to SQ-15U)
SOLVED PAPERS (2013-14 TO 2016-17)  (SP-IU to SP-20U)

